Charles B. Davenport Papers ca.1903-1940 Mss.B.D27
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Charles B. Davenport Papers, 1878-1944; 43 linear feet (Box 1-97)
  - Cooley, James S., 1901 Apr. 29; 1 item (Box 13)
  - Cooley, R. A., 1906 Dec. 26 - 1907 Jan. 8; 2 items (Box 13)
  - Coolidge, Harold J., Jr., 1931 June 16; 2 items (Box 13)
  - Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897, 1892 Jan. 6 - 1896 Jan. 18; 2 items (Box 13)
  - Copeland, Edwin Bingham, 1873-?, 1900 Mar. 18 - 1901 Oct. 14; 4 items (Box 13)
  - Copeland, Royal S. (Royal Samuel), 1868-1938, 1926 Dec. 4 - 1930 Dec. 24; 8 items (Box 13)
  - Cori, Carl J., 1891 Jan. 18 - 1930 Nov. 11; 22 items (Box 13)
    Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War I -- Impact on science; Zoology
  - Coriat, Isidor H., 1875-?, 1920 Oct. 15-21; 2 items (Box 13)
  - Corley, James A. (Box 13)
  - Corner, George Washington, 1889-?, 1919-1939; 2 folders (61 items) (Box 13)
    Bibliographical matters; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Embryology, developmental genetics; Genetics; Human genetics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Publication
    - Folder 1, 1919 Dec. 19 - 1920 Nov. 26; 26 items (Box 13)
    - Folder 2, 1921 Mar. 23 - 1939 Nov. 14; 35 items (Box 13)
  - Correia, Germano, 1928 Apr. 18 (Box 13)
  - Correns, Carl, 1864-1933, 1904 June 2 - 1928 May 26; 26 items (Box 13)
  - Corwin, Edward Henry Lewinski, 1885-?, 1922 Mar. 10 - 1933 May 10; 36 items (Box 13)
  - Coulter, John Merle, 1851-1928, 1903 Mar. 28 - 1925 Dec. 30; 31 items (Box 13)
  - Coulter, Samuel Monds, 1860-?, 1902 Jan. 16 - July 21; 3 items (Box 13)
  - Council of National Defense, 1917 July 10-18; 6 items (Box 13)
  - Courtis, Stuart A. (Stuart Appleton), 1874-1969, 1932 July 14 - Sept. 13; 3 items (Box 13)
  - Cowdry, E. V. (Edmund Vincent), 1888-1975, 1926-1931; 2 folders (49 items) (Box 13)
    Bermuda Biological Station; Embryology, developmental genetics; Human genetics; Publication; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder 1, 1926 Feb. 23 - 1927 Dec. 16; 30 items (Box 13)
    - Folder 2, 1928 Jan. 30 - 1931 Apr. 7; 19 items (Box 13)
  - Cowles, Henry Chandler, 1869-1939, 1900 June 15 - Dec. 29; 12 items (Box 13)
  - Cowles, Rheinhart Parker, 1872-?, 1916 June 21 - Sept. 2; 4 items (Box 13)
  - Cox, Esther, 1905 June 17; 1 item (Box 13)
  - Crabb, Edward D. (Edward Drane), 1890-?, 1930 Nov. 26 - Dec. 20; 2 items (Box 13)
  - Craig, Wallace, 1876-?, 1920 Aug. 2 - 1925 July 2; 15 items (Box 13)
  - Craig, William F., 1904 Apr. 20; 1 item (Box 13)
  - Cramer, R. M., 1922 Feb. - 1927 Jan. 24; 20 items (Box 13)
  - Crampton, C. Ward (Charles Ward), 1877-1964, 1918-1933; 3 folders (100 items) (Box 13-14)
    Anthropology; Eugenics; Human genetics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1, 1918 Jan. 24 - 1927 Dec. 29; 28 items (Box 13)
    - Folder 2, 1928 Jan. 3 - 1929 July 5; 27 items (Box 13)
    - Folder 3, 1930 Nov. 14 - 1933 May 4; 45 items (Box 14)
  - Crampton, Henry Edward, 1875-?, 1904-1925; 2 folders (104 items) (Box 14)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder 1, 1904 Jan. 11 - 1909 Mar. 27; 56 items (Box 14)
    - Folder 2, 1914 Mar. 21 - 1925 Apr. 21; 48 items (Box 14)
  - Creamer, John, 1920 Aug. 2 - 1921 Aug. 1; 9 items (Box 14)
  - Crider, F. J., 1927 July 7-14; 2 items (Box 14)
  - Crookshank, F. G. (Francis Graham), 1873-1933, 1924 Dec. 6 - 1927 Jan. 24; 7 items (Box 14)
  - Cross, Whitman, 1854-1949, 1914 June 11 - 1929 July 5; 21 items (Box 14)
  - Crotty, Millia A., 1934 Mar. 4; 1 item (Box 14)
  - Crowell, Roy C., 1933 Apr. 12-19; 3 items (Box 14)
  - Crozier, William John, 1921 May 16 - 1932 Nov. 1; 8 items (Box 14)
  - Cuenot, Lucien Claude Marie Julien, 1866-1951, 1904 May 27 - 1922 Dec. 22; 23 items (Box 14)
  - Cumings, Edgar Roscoe, 1874-?, 1903 Feb. 18 - 1917 May 15; 6 items (Box 14)
  - Cumming, Hugh Smith, 1869-?, 1920 Dec. 18 - 1933 Oct. 26; 7 items (Box 14)
  - Cuniberti, Fernando, 1922 Feb. 3-16; 3 items (Box 14)
  - Cunningham, Joseph Thomas, 1859-1935, 1904 Aug. 8 - 1909 May 21; 4 items (Box 14)
  - Curti, Mrs. Margaret (Wooster), 1891-?, 1933 Nov. 20-27; 2 items (Box 14)
  - Curtis, Winterton C. (Winterton Conway), 1875-1965, 1923 Jan. 25 - 1936 June 15; 37 items (Box 14)
  - Curtiss, Charles F. (Charles Francis), 1904 Apr. 22 - 1921 Dec. 15; 4 items (Box 14)
  - Curtius, Friedrich, 1896-?, 1933 Apr. 4 - May 2; 5 items (Box 14)
  - Dahl, Knut, 1902 Oct. 21; 1 item (Box 14)
  - Dall, William Healey, 1845-1927, 1900 Jan. 20 - Feb. 14; 2 items (Box 14)
  - Dana, Charles Loomis, 1852-1935, 1917 Feb. 12 - 1928 Jan. 10 (Box 14)
  - Dana, Edward Salisbury, 1849-1935, 1922 Nov. 3 - 1924 May 1; 6 items (Box 14)
  - Danforth, C. H. (Charles Haskell), 1909 Mar. 25 - 1942 May 27; 58 items (Box 14)
    Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Embryology, developmental genetics; Eugenics; Human genetics; Mouse genetics; Poultry genetics
  - Daniels, Francis B., 1909 June 21 - July 10; 3 items (Box 14)
  - Daniels, Josephus, 1862-1948, 1914 Dec. 24 - 1917 Sept. 27; 3 items (Box 14)
  - Dann, H. E., 1908 Nov. 11 - 1911 Nov. 6; 28 items (Box 14)
  - Darbishire, A. D. (Arthur Dukinfield), 1879-1915, 1904 May 10 - 1910 May 28; 21 items (Box 14)
  - Darwin, Francis, 1848-1925, 1907 Jan. 26 - Mar. 29; 4 items (Box 14)
  - Darwin, Leonard, 1850-1943, 1921-1937; 4 folders (148 items) (Box 14)
    Biographical and personal data; Conferences and symposia; Eugenics; Human genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; International Congress of Eugenics -- Third Congress; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War I -- Impact on science
    - Folder 1, 1921 Oct. 3 - 1922 Dec. 24; 25 items (Box 14)
      - Davenport to Leonard Darwin, 1922 November 11 (Box 14)
    - Folder 2, 1922 Dec. 22 - 1924 Dec. 27; 40 items (Box 14)
    - Folder 3, 1925 Jan. 28 - 1926 Oct. 22; 38 items (Box 14)
    - Folder 4, 1927 Mar. 31 - 1937 Dec. 29; 45 items (Box 14)
  - Dashiell, L. M., 1914 Oct. 29 - 1915 Sept. 28; 40 items (Box 14)
  - Davenport, A. B. (Amzi Benedict), b. 1817, 1857 Dec. 12 - 1885 May 5; 3 items (Box 14)
  - Davenport, Mrs. A. B., 1890 July 11 - 1895 Jan. 27; 7 items (Box 14)
  - Davenport, Charles B. (Box 14-32)
    Anthropology; Evolution; History of biology, especially genetics -- Darwin, Charles; Human evolution, physical anthropology; Human genetics; Poultry genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Abstracts, 1923 - 1933 Oct. 14; 45 items (Box 14)
      Bibliographical matters -- Abstracts
    - Account books, 1879 Mar. 1 - 1923 Jan. 27; 4 books (Box 15)
      - Book 1, 1879 Mar. 1 - 1892 Sept. 21; 1 book (Box 15)
      - Book 2, 1894 June 24 - 1898 Nov. 30; 1 book (Box 15)
      - Book 3, 1894 Nov. 29 - 1898 Aug. 17; 1 book (Box 15)
      - Book 4, 1922 Jan. 1 - 1923 Jan. 27; 1 book (Box 15)
    - Alleged Case of Inheritance of Acquired Characters, ca. 1933; 5 items inc. 4 copies (Box 14)
    - Autobiographical, 1916-1940; 3 folders (40 items) (Box 14, 22)
      Biographical and personal data
      - Folder 1, 1916 - Sept. 26; 12 items (Box 14)
      - Folder 2, 1927 June - 1933; 17 items (Box 14)
      - Folder 3, 1930-1940; 11 items (Box 22)
    - Background and Early Studies Which Led to the Est. of the ERO, ca. 1933; 1 item (Box 22)
    - Bibliography, 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Folder 1, 1931; 10 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 2, 1941; 17 items (Box 22)
    - Book reviews, 1913-1944; 2 folders (44 items) (Box 22)
      Reviews -- Books
      - Folder 1, 1913-1924; 21 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 2, 1925-1944; 23 items (Box 22)
    - Books, n.d.; 1 items (74 pages) (Box 22)
    - Books purchased, 1894 Jan. 16 - 1942 Sept. 4; 3 folders (Box 22)
      - Folder 1, 1923 Feb. 9 - 1935 Aug. 1; 87 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 2, 1907 Apr. 20 - 1935 Jan. 10; 97 items (Box 22)
      - Folder 3, 1894 Jan. 16 - 1942 Sept. 4; 72 items (Box 22)
    - Breeding poultry, n.d.; 1 item (Box 22)
    - Clubs, 1893 May 26 - 1933 Feb. 1; 11 items (Box 22)
    - Cold Spring Harbor - School Committee, 1941 - 1942 Mar. 3; 8 items (Box 22)
    - Commencement part, Harvard, 1889, 1 item (Box 22)
    - Development of the Arm Length and of the Intermembral Index, 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Folder 1, n.d.; 1 item (Box 22)
      - Folder 2, n.d.; 1 item (Box 22)
    - Diaries, 1878-1943; 97 items (Box 16-21)
      Appointment books, diaries, notebooks; Biographical and personal data; Birds; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1878-1879; 2 items (Box 16)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1881-1882; 6 items (Box 16)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1881-1882; 2 items (Box 16)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1884; 2 items (Box 16)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1885; 2 items (Box 16)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1886; 3 items (Box 16)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1889-1892; 2 items (Box 16)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1899-1901; 1 item (Box 17)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1901-1902; 4 items (Box 17)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1903; 3 items (Box 17)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1904; 4 items (Box 17)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1905; 2 items (Box 17)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1905-1913; 1 item (Box 18)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1906-1907; 3 items (Box 18)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1908-1909; 3 items (Box 18)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1908-1910; 2 items (Box 18)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1910-1911; 4 items (Box 18)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1912-1913; 3 items (Box 18)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1914; 2 items (Box 18)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1915; 2 items (Box 18)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1916-1919; 4 items (Box 18)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1920; 1 item (Box 19)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1920-1921; 3 items (Box 19)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1922; Passport (Box 19)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1922-1924; 3 items (Box 19)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1922; Notes on trip to Europe (Box 19)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1920-1924; 1 item (Box 19)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1923-1924; 3 items (Box 19)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1925; Passport (Box 19)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1925; 2 items (Box 19)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1925; 2 books and loose pages (Box 19)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1925-1929; 2 items (Box 19)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1930; loose diary pages (Box 19)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1929-1930; 2 items (Box 19)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1931; 2 items (Box 19)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1931; 3 items (Box 20)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1930-1934; 1 item (Box 20)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1932-1933; 3 items (Box 20)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1934; 3 items (Box 20)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1935-1936; 3 items (Box 20)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1937-1938; 2 items (Box 21)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1935-1939; 2 items (Box 21)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1939; 3 items (Box 21)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1940-1942; 3 items (Box 21)
      - Davenport, C.B. Diaries, 1940-1944; 3 items (Box 21)
    - Discussions, n.d.; 2 items (Box 22)
    - Effect of the Darwinian Doctrines on Biology, 1 item (Box 22)
    - Experimental Evolution Lectures, 1902-1903; 2 folders (Box 23)
      Folders are empty. For content, see below, Experimental Evolution Lectures.
    - Experimental Morphology, n.d.; 7 folders (Box 23)
    - Family records, 1909 Mar. 25 - 1944 May 1; 13 items (Box 23)
    - Financial matters, 1923 June 7; 3 folders (Box 23)
      - Folder 1, 1904 Nov. 29 - 1923 Dec. 20; 32 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 2, 1924 Mar. 15 - 1925 Dec. 31; 33 items (Box 23)
      - Folder 3, 1926 Jan. 28 - 1935 Feb. 14; 34 items (Box 23)
    - Fingerprinting, 1933 Mar. 4 - n.d.; 19 items (Box 23)
    - From Generation to Generation, n.d.; 7 folders (Box 23-24)
      - Folder 1 (Box 23)
      - Folder 2 (Box 23)
      - Folder 3 (Box 23)
      - Folder 4 (Box 23)
      - Folder 5 (Box 24)
      - Folder 6 (Box 24)
      - Folder 7 (Box 24)
    - Graduate reports - Harvard 1888, 1888 Jan. - Dec. 22; 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Folder 1, 1888 Jan. - Apr. 14; 2 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 2, 1888 May 31 - Dec. 22; 2 items (Box 24)
    - Guide to Genetical Sensory and Mental Measurements, 1931; 1 item (Box 24)
    - Gulf Biological Expedition, n.d.; 3 items (Box 24)
    - Heredity Lectures - Universtiy of Chicago, 1901; 2 folders (Box 24)
      Embryology, developmental genetics; Human genetics; Lectures, public speaking; University of Chicago
    - Individual Variation, 1 item (Box 24)
    - Inheritance of Acquired Dynamical Qualities, 1903; 1 item (Box 24)
    - Itineraries, Expenses, Etc., 1904-1943; 6 folders (Box 24)
      - Folder 1, 1904-1927; 28 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 2, 1928-1929; 54 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 3, 1930; 38 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 4, 1931; 31 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 5, 1932; 24 items (Box 24)
      - Folder 6, 1933-1943; 49 items (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1902-1934 (Box 24-28)
      Behavioral genetics, IQ; Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Embryology, developmental genetics; Eugenics; Evolution; Genetics; History of biology, especially genetics; Human evolution, physical anthropology; Human genetics; Lectures, public speaking; Political issues; Poultry genetics; Publication; Race crossing; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
      - "On Feebleminded Persons", 1 draft (Box 24)
      - A Biologist's View of the Negro Problem, n.d.; 1 item (Box 24)
      - About Eugenics, 1924 Mar. 19; 1 item (Box 24)
      - About Eugenics, n.d.; 2 items (Box 24)
      - Aims and Methods in Anthropometry, 1 item (Box 24)
      - Aims, Works, Results, of the E.R.O., 1922; 5 items (Box 24)
      - Alcoholism in a Rural Community of Defectives, 1912 Nov. 25; 1 item (Box 24)
      - Anatomical Features of Growth During the Second Decade, 1930; 3 items (Box 24)
      - Animals and the World About Them, 1 item (Box 24)
      - Application of Mendel's Law to Human Heredity, 1 item (Box 24)
      - Battle Creek Lectures, n.d.; 2 items (Box 24)
      - Best Index of Build, 1920 Aug. 9; 1 item (Box 24)
      - Biological Laboratory and its Offspring, 1 item (Box 24)
      - Biology and Fundamentalists, 1 item (Box 24)
      - Biology at Cold Spring Harbor, ca. 1917 (?); 1 item (Box 24)
      - Bird Sanctuary, Jones Beach (renamed "Oyster Bay. Taxpayer's League. Citizen's Joint Beach Committee) (Box 24)
      - Blood Grouping, n.d.; 2 items (Box 24)
      - Body Build, 1924 Feb.; 1 item (Box 24)
      - Body Build and Its Inheritance, 2 folders (Box 25)
      - Body Form and Function of Sixteen Year Old Students..., 1933 Mar. 13; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Breeding Poultry, 1908 July 20-24; 1 notebook (Box 25)
      - Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1910 Dec. 12; 2 drafts (Box 25)
      - Characters in Mongrel vs. Pure Bred Individuals, 1 item (Box 25)
      - Chromosome, 1931 Nov. 21; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Chromosome Variations, 1926 Jan. 18; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Combinations of Hair and Eye Color in Man, 2 drafts (Box 25)
      - Combinations of these "Heredity Tendancies", 1 item (Box 25)
      - Committee on Theoretic Research in Heredity, n.d.; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Comparative Social Traits of Various Races, 1921 Aug. 11; 2 drafts (Box 25)
      - Comparative Study of Method of Selection for Academies and Societies, 1933 Sept. 19; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Coordinates in Anthropometry, n.d.; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Cripples, n.d.; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Development of Eugenics, n.d.; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Diet and Individuals, 1 item (Box 25)
      - Difficulties in Mosquito Control, ca. 1902; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Direction of Genetical Investigation, 1925 Oct.; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Do Races Differ in Mental Capacity?, 1924 Mar.; 2 items (Box 25)
      - Dr. Galloway's "Canary Breeding", 1910; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Ecology of Epilepsy, n.d.; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Effect of Alcohol upon Animals, n.d.; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Endocrines in Relation to Development and Heredity, 1927 Mar. 4; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Eugenics, n.d.; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Eugenics. (Harvard Club?), n.d.; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Eugenics and A.E. Wiggam, 1 item (Box 25)
      - Eugenics and Charity, 1 item (Box 25)
      - Eugenics as a Religion, 1916; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Eugenics in relation to Medicine, n.d.; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Eugenics in Relation to Public Welfare, n.d.; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Evidences of Man's Ancestral History..., 1933; 7 drafts (Box 25)
      - Evolution, n.d.; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Factor Hypothesis..., 1909; 1item (Box 25)
      - Factors of Heredity and Environment in Criminality, 1 item (Box 25)
      - Family Performance as a basis for selection in sheep, n.d.; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Family Studies on Mongolian Dwarfs, 2 folders (Box 25)
      - Feeble Mindness as a General Retardation in Development, 1924 Oct. 28; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Gene, 1931 Nov. 21; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Genetics, 1931 Nov. 21; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Genetics in Relation to Biography, 1932 Dec.; 4 drafts (Box 25)
      - George Whiting Flagg, n.d.; 3 items (Box 25)
      - Growth of Children, 1932 Dec. 9; 3 drafts (Box 25)
      - Hair Changes as Age Markers, n.d.; 2 drafts (Box 25)
      - Hearing in Children of whom Both Parents have Otosclerosis, n.d.; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Hereditary Factors in Development, 1921 Dec. 29; 2 drafts (Box 25)
      - Hereditary Heaviness of Eye-Brows, n.d.; 1 item (Box 25)
      - Heredity, 1927 - 1929 Nov. 12; 2 folders (Box 26)
      - Heredity and Culture in Body Build, 2 drafts (Box 26)
      - Heredity and Disease, 1931; 5 drafts (Box 26)
      - Heredity and Eugenics, 1920; 1 item (Box 26)
      - Heredity and its Interaction with Environment, 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Heredity and Longevity, 1928; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Heredity and Mendel's Law, 1907; 1 item (Box 26)
      - Heredity and Race Eugenics, 1927; 3 drafts (Box 26)
      - Heredity in its Application to Animal and Plant Breeding and to Man, 1910; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Heredity in Man, 1909; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Heredity in Man and Animals, 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Heredity in Relation to Insanity, n.d.; 1 item (Box 26)
      - Heredity of Bone Defects, n.d.; 1 item (Box 26)
      - Heredity of Disease, n.d.; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Heredity of Nasal Brow, n.d.; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Heredity of Otosclerosis, 1932 June 4; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Heredity of Physical Defects, n.d.; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Heredity of Physical Traits, n.d.; 2 drafts (Box 26)
      - Heredity of Stature, n.d.; 2 drafts (Box 26)
      - Heredity of Twin Births, 1920 Jan. 21; 1 drafts (Box 26)
      - Heredity Tendency to Form Nerve Tumors, 2 drafts (Box 26)
      - Horns in Sheep, 1912; 4 items (Box 26)
      - Hospital Development Committee, n.d.; 1 item (Box 26)
      - How a Eugenicist Looks at the matter of Marriage, 1928 May 5; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - How does a Child Grow?, n.d.; 2 drafts (Box 26)
      - How Early in Ontogeny do Human Racial Characteristics Show Themselves?, 1933 Dec. 18; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Human Growth Curve, n.d.; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Human Metamorphosis, 1926 Jan.; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Hybridism, 1931 Nov. 21; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Immigration, n.d.; 2 drafts (Box 26)
      - Immigration Policy of the United States, n.d.; 2 draft (Box 26)
      - Imperfections of Dominance, 1910; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Importance of Eugenical Field Work For the State of Rhode Island, 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Importance of Heredity in Social Affairs, n.d.; 1draft (Box 26)
      - Importance of medical biographies, n.d.; 3 drafts (Box 26)
      - Importance of Quantitative Study of Variation for Medicine, ca. 1900; 1draft (Box 26)
      - In How Far and In What Way is it True that a Child is Bound by Heredity, 1909 Mar. 3; 3 drafts (Box 26)
      - Incremental and Differential Growth, 1933 Dec. 29; 2 drafts (Box 26)
      - Influence of Heredity on History, 1912; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Influence of the Male in Production of Human Twins, 1920 Jan.; 3 drafts (Box 26)
      - Inheritance in Pedigree Breeding in Poultry, 1907; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Inheritance of Dent in Forehead, ca. 1915; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Inheritance of Disease, 1933 Apr. 15 - June 2; 2 items (Box 26)
      - Inheritance of Intellectual and Moral Traits by Children, 3 drafts (Box 26)
      - Is the Crossing of Races Useful?, 1929 Nov. 12; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Is there inheritance of twinning tendency from the father's side?, 1927- 1928 Jan.; 6 drafts (Box 26)
      - Is W. R. Day related to Jeremiah Day?, n.d.; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Joint Action of Genetical and Environmental Factors in Child Development, 1933 May 22; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Kristine Bonnevie: Studies on Papillary Patterns of Human Fingers, n.d.; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Laws of Inheritance, 1929 Jan. 23; 2 drafts (Box 26)
      - Light thrown Experimental Study of Heredity, 1912; 1 draft (Box 26)
      - Lowell - Cabot - Putnam - Russell - Jackson. The first families of Boston, n.d.; 2drafts (Box 26)
      - Mammalian Growth Curves, n.d.; 2 drafts (Box 26)
      - Man from the Standpoint of the Student of Genetics, 1 draft (Box 27)
      - Man is an animal, n.d.; 1 draft (Box 27)
      - Marriage Laws and Customs, 1 draft (Box 27)
      - Measurement of Men, n.d.; 1 draft (Box 27)
      - Measurements of the Body, 1933 Mar.; 1 draft (Box 27)
      - Mechanics of Heredity, n.d.; 1 draft (Box 27)
      - Medico-Legal Aspects of Eugenics, 1914; 1 draft (Box 27)
      - Memo for Human Behavior Committee, 1933 Apr. 24; 2 drafts (Box 27)
      - Memoir on A. G. Mayer, [1922 July 15]; 3 drafts (Box 27)
      - Memoir on W. B. James, n.d.; 1 item (Box 27)
      - Memorandum on a Fundamental Study of the Nature of Sex, 1929 Dec. 30; 2 drafts (Box 27)
      - Mendelian Inhaeritance as a Factor in Organic Evolution, 2 drafts (Box 27)
      - Mendelism, 1931 Nov. 21; 1 draft (Box 27)
      - Mendelism in Man, 1932 May 25; 3 drafts (Box 27)
      - Methods in Comparative Racial Psychology, 1929; 4 drafts (Box 27)
      - Miscellany, n.d.; 15 items (Box 27)
      - Modern Laws of Heredity with Special Reference to Cattle Breeding, n.d.; 1 draft (Box 27)
      - Modification of the Germ Plasm, 1923; 2 drafts (Box 27)
      - Mongolians and Mongoloids, 3 drafts (Box 27)
      - Multiple Sclerosis, n.d.; 1 draft (Box 27)
      - Nature of Behavior, 1925; 2 drafts (Box 27)
      - Nature of Hereditary Mental Defect, n.d.; 1 draft (Box 27)
      - New Case of a Sex-Limited Character in Poultry, 1912; 1 draft (Box 27)
      - Note for Quarterly Publication, 1921 Jan. 24; 1 item (Box 27)
      - Observations made at Letchworth Village, 1933 Oct. 12; 1 item (Box 27)
      - On Australian Aborigines, n.d.; 11 items (Box 27)
      - On Edward Laurens Mark, 1922 May 15; 1 draft (Box 27)
      - On Eugenics, n.d.; 1 draft (Box 27)
      - On H. S. Jennings' Research, n.d.; 2 drafts (Box 27)
      - On Mendel, 1 draft (Box 27)
      - On the Need of Checking in Anthropometry, 1932 July 12; 2 drafts (Box 27)
      - On Utilizing the Facts of Juvenile Promise and Family History, 1 draft (Box 27)
      - Organization of an Institute for Human Biology, 1926; 2 drafts (Box 27)
      - Origin of Species, n.d.; 1 draft (Box 27)
      - Our Feet, 1 draft (Box 27)
      - Outline of plans for developing biology at Cold Springs Harbor, n.d.; 1 draft (Box 27)
      - Physical Basis of Human Behavior, 1921 Nov. 11; 1 draft (Box 27)
      - Physical Development in Boys, 1926 Nov. 5; 1 draft (Box 27)